<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sanchaara</title>
    <description>Namma Payana..
</description>
    <link>http://sanchaara.in/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sanchaara.in/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 18:07:19 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 18:07:19 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Roopkund Quest</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, the Himalayas! A paradise for some and a challenge for others. I’ve always wanted to go to the Himalayas and experience it first hand. I wanted to see what the excitement was all about. Things fell into place during December 2014 and we were off on a trek to Dalhousie. I guess that’s where the mountains cast a spell on me. They say that the mountains pull you back. And in May 2015, they did. This time, the destination was Roopkund, the mystery lake!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a photographer and I get excited about astronomy as well. I’ve been seeing the images of The Milky Way for a long time on television. When a friend of mine, Setu, wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://secondclassleeper.wordpress.com/2014/11/06/the-night-sky-peacock-story-behind-the-milky-way-image/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about an image of The Milky Way he had captured, I was spellbound! At that moment, I knew what my next destination was; Roopkund! Coincidentally, a bunch of folks at my workplace were planning on a trek to Roopkund as well. We registered for the Roopkund trek via &lt;a href=&quot;http://indiahikes.in/&quot;&gt;Indiahikes&lt;/a&gt;, came up with an itinerary, purchased the supplies and we were off!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you read on, do take a look at the trailer that I’ve compiled. The full length is still in work-in-progress status. I’ll update the blog once it’s complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[embed]https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bMXKTBm-vT8[/embed]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Preparations for the trek:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Itinerary&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a 11-day trip in total, from Bangalore to Bangalore. We took a flight from Bangalore to Delhi, followed by a train from Delhi to Katgodham the same night. From Katgodham, we went to Nainital by bus and stayed there for a couple of days. From Nainital, we went to Lohajung Base Camp by a rented car. Roopkund trek begins from Lohajung Base Camp. After six days, we returned to Lohajung Base Camp. From Lohajung Base Camp, we went to Katgodham by a rented car. We took a train from Katgodham to Delhi, followed by a flight back to Bangalore. This was a well-planned trip and we didn’t have to make decisions on-the-go. The flight tickets, train tickets, rented car and the trek registration were booked in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Budget&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming up with an cost-effective itinerary is challenging indeed. The entire trip cost me around ₹30,000. The registration for the trek is around ₹10,500. Make sure you book your flight tickets early. Since we were flying from Bangalore to Delhi, it cost around ₹10,000, inclusive of onward and return journey. The train tickets between Delhi and Katgodham cost around ₹1,500 I think. I had bought most of my trekking equipments from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decathlon.in&quot;&gt;Decathlon&lt;/a&gt;, so I’m not including the cost of those equipments over here. I’d say the cost of the equipment would be around ₹16,000 - ₹18,000. Nainital detour, car rental and other miscellaneous costs lead upto around ₹8,500.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Physical Fitness&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roopkund is a high altitude trek with moderate-difficult rating. It is recommended that you keep yourself physically fit. Since I cycle regularly to office, I didn’t exclusively prepare for the trek. The Indiahikes team recommends that you start with slow jogs and increase your pace and distance. By the time your trek starts you need to be able to jog for 4.5 kms under 30 mins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Roopkund experience:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day 1 | 15th May, 2015 | Bangalore - Delhi - Katgodham&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We (Navaneeth, Kavya, Shiva, Divya and me) had booked a 5pm flight from Bangalore to Delhi. It was bound to reach Delhi by 7:45pm and it ran a bit late. We had a train to catch from Delhi to Katgodham at 10:45pm, or so we thought. There are a whole bunch of railway stations in Delhi and it’s very confusing if you’re new to the city. We double-checked that it was the Old Delhi Railway station that we’re departing from. Battling the traffic, we somehow made it to the railway station at 10:10pm. Since we had another half an hour to go, we thought of having dinner. We waited at the restaurant till 10:20pm and figured it’d be late. Me, Kavya and Divya started towards the platform, while Navaneeth and Shiva were to join us later with the packed food. Just when we reached the platform and were searching for our compartment, the train started to move! It was 10:30pm. We had split up while searching, and had to get on the train in different compartments. We had no clue if Navaneeth and Shiva had made it. We gave them a call and found out that they had boarded after quite a bit of sprinting. We reached Katgodham the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A piece of advice, it’s not good enough if you’re on time. Reach early and always keep buffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day 2 | 16th May, 2015 | Katgodham - Nainital&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train station was pretty empty when we reached early morning. After freshening up a bit, we had tea and took a bus to Nainital. Buses are quite frequent along this route. We reached Nainital in about 1.5 hours. We had booked the government rest house and it was pretty good. It turned out to be economical and we had a good view of Nainital lake from the room. After a boat ride in Nainital lake, we roamed around the streets of Nainital. It’s a pretty good place with good food to eat. We went to the market and explored the place a bit. As night fell, the lake lit up with the reflections from the nearby households on the slope. It was a wonderful sight to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/18291962785_69ed4845f1_k.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-350 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/18291962785_69ed4845f1_k.jpg?w=660&quot; alt=&quot;Roopkund_Blog_Nainital&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day 3 | 17th May, 2015 | Nainital&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hit the Zoo! Yes, there’s a high altitude Zoo in Nainital. The ‘ascent’ up the route from the lake to the zoo itself is tiring. If we’re struggling to climb along this simple route, we’re screwed for the trek, we thought. After a few photo sessions, we left for Naina Devi temple. Next, we visited Eco Cave Gardens. I recorded a few shots from my recently bought GoPro over there. I had never given it a roll before. Little did I know that this would turn out to be a bad decision. And I had no clue how the videos/images were turning out to be. On the way back, we shopped for some souvenirs and returned to the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day 4 | 18th May, 2015 | Nainital - Lohajung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 4 was all about hitting the road. We had rented a car and it takes around 6-7 hours to reach Lohajung from Nainital. The route is scenic. You get occasional glimpses of lower Himalayan ranges. It’s like they’re playing hide and seek with you. The needle-like leaves along the route indicated that the area would be covered in snow during winter. It’s amazing how evolution has led life to thrive in harsh conditions. We reached Lohajung Base camp around 3 in the afternoon. Other trekkers hadn’t arrived yet. We were greeted by our trek leader and camp leader. Ours was the second batch in the trekking programme. It’s always better to book an early ticket for treks involving snow. We finished the onsite registration and collected the trekking poles. Trust me, you &lt;b&gt;need&lt;/b&gt; a trekking pole! As the evening fell, other trekkers started to pour in, and so did the rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_345” align=”aligncenter” width=”660”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/17669307454_c125ee7bd9_k.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-345 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/17669307454_c125ee7bd9_k.jpg?w=660&quot; alt=&quot;Roopkund_Blog_Lohajung&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Sunlight piercing through the clouds after a moderate rainfall[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked towards the direction of Roopkund. Dark gloomy clouds hovering over the trek path was not something we wanted to see. After a while, we were briefed about the trek, it’s difficulty, do’s and dont’s. Quite frankly, I was a bit eery after listening to how things could go wrong. Apparently, AMS (Acute Mountain Sickness) is more serious than I initially thought it was. We were advised to start off on a Diamox dosage, which I didn’t. Just when I was mentally preparing for the trek, bad news struck! The forest department had closed down the trekking path due to unforeseen circumstances. I was heartbroken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can’t be happening! The two main reasons I was very excited about the Roopkund trek was The Milky Way and the skeletons. I wanted to make a travelogue. I wanted to trek on the snow. I wanted to experience the trek! But it looked like the mountains had other plans. I went to bed, disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day 5 | 19th May, 2015 | Lohajung - Ghairoli Patal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ghairoli Patal Camp | 10,200ft | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.co.in/maps/place/30%C2%B011&#39;59.5%22N+79%C2%B039&#39;09.1%22E/@30.199873,79.652528,766m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x0&quot;&gt;(30.199873, 79.652528)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up with a glimmer of hope that the forest department would allow for the trek. Even if the forest department allowed the trek, what if nature had other plans for us, I thought in a corner of my mind. But it didn’t matter. The trek was still closed. We decided to hike to a nearby hill. Well, something is better than nothing. This was a good opportunity to socialize with the trekkers. We were a pretty diverse group. We had doctors, a captain of a ship, an enthusiastic professor, grad students, photographers, a 13-year old and IT guys (ofcourse). I started shooting the videos for my travelogue on the top of the hill. The trek leader briskly gathered us around for an announcement; We have to rush back for an important announcement. The trek was on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were behind schedule though. By the time we got back to the base camp, it was already 10:30 and we had to leave by 11:45. The actual trek starts from Wan village. It’s an hour’s drive from Lohajung to Wan. We started the actual trek at 1 in the afternoon. If things went according to schedule, we would’ve covered 3/4th the distance to Ghairoli Patal. The reason that people prefer to start early is the rapidly changing and unpredictable Himalayan weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indiahikes follow a very good practice of supplying eco bags for the “Green Trails” campaign. The ideology behind this is campaign is to leave behind a cleaner the trekking path than the one you tread on. A guide from the surrounding area accompanies the trekkers for every trek. At the start of the trek, there is a small Nanda Devi mandir. We prayed and flagged off the trek. “Roopkund, here we come!”, I thought. This portion involves a small ascent, followed by a descent to the Neel Ganga river, and an ascent to the Ghairoli Patal. The initial ascent is a stony laid-out path. The descent to Neel Ganga is like any other hillside trek. We relaxed a bit at Neel Ganga and started the ascent. Boy, what an ascent that was! A few got breathless and most of us were tired. No wonder people hire mules to carry their luggage. But I was determined &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; to hire one, although my bag was extra heavy (why? read on!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the evening set, the bright blue sky turned gloomy grey. It was about to rain and we took our ponchos out. They’re not as light as you’d expect them to be. Luckily, the rain stopped after a drizzle. We finally reached Ghairoli Patal at 6. There is no electrical connectivity from this point onwards. Mobile signals were performing a balancing act. I could see people roaming around the camp hooked on to the little bars on their mobile screens. And as usual, I started shooting for my travelogue. The night set in and we were tired from the journey. We had dinner and crept into our sleeping bags for a good night’s sleep. I knew that the next day was gonna exciting, but I had largely underestimated it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day 6 | 20th May, 2015 | Ghairoli Patal - Bedni Bugyal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bedni Bugyal Camp | 11,700ft | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.co.in/maps/place/30%C2%B012&#39;19.6%22N+79%C2%B039&#39;44.2%22E/@30.205447,79.662283,766m/data=!3m2!1e3!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x0&quot;&gt;(30.205447, 79.662283)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I open my eyes all of a sudden and my watch reads 3:30. I’m not a morning person. In fact, I often sleep at 3:30 and this felt strange. Very strange. I don’t know how I woke up, but I realized why I did. All I had to was step out of my tent into the cold and look up at the Himalayan night sky. Gazillions of stars staring at you! The light from their cores must’ve traveled for millions of years, only to hit you in the eye all at once. I was ecstatic. Instantly, I knew what I had to do. I pulled out my camera, setup my tripod and pointed it to the South sky. This was the moment that I had been waiting for.. The Milky Way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_348” align=”aligncenter” width=”660”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/18288020972_bc85ebb7c5_k.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-348 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/18288020972_bc85ebb7c5_k.jpg?w=660&quot; alt=&quot;Roopkund_Blog_Gharoli_Patal&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Milky Way![/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/img_7850.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-352 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/img_7850.jpg?w=660&quot; alt=&quot;The *excited* writeup!&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;990&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know I was gonna fulfil one of dreams this early in the trek. The average human tendency to share the excitement drove me to wake Navaneeth up and show the images. I wanted to shoot more and it was already 4. By the time I followed the Milky Way’s tail, I started to see a blue tinge of sunlight in my photos. Obviously, I had woken up too late. Needless to say, I wanted to try again. Opportunities like these are very rare indeed. Here’s an excerpt from the night’s script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a glimmer of satisfaction in my eyes, I crawled back into my sleeping bag again. After a couple of hours of sleep, it was time to prepare for the next higher camp. The trek leaders had an oxymeter. They checked the oxygen levels in the blood twice a day for every trekker. We left for the next camp, Bedni Bugyal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This path starts with an ascent in the dense forests till Ali Bugyal, with occasional descents. From Ali bugyal, it’s a gradual ascent followed by a slight descent to Bedni Bugyal. The trek through the dense forest was not as tiring as the previous day’s ascent. The Himalayan terrain changes every 1,000 ft. It’s not a gradual change at all. You can notice the change unfolding right before your eyes. It was bright and sunny on this path. It’s advised that you keep yourself hydrated at all times. Have small pints of water frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t particularly keeping a tab on my camera batteries. After all, I was carrying a DSLR, and DSLR batteries are supposed to last for days. Well, they do, under normal conditions. But Himalayas is &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; normal. I had carried one extra battery thinking that it would be sufficient. By the middle of the day, I had exhausted one battery pack. But that’s ok. I had another whole battery left, right? Wrong! I hadn’t kept the battery warm and the charge had reduced to 1/3rd overnight. Well, there goes my dream to capture The Milky Way again. I still had my GoPro, but that’s not gonna help me in capturing the stars, does it?  Besides, the GoPro batteries ran into the same problem and I didn’t have any spares. I had taken my portable charger as well. I occasionally charged my GoPro with little, but sufficient, success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember folks, always keep your batteries warm and carry spare ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ali bugyal is a beautiful meadow, covered with a blanket of grass and flowers. The forest ends abruptly, opening up a meadow. It’s a beautiful sight to watch. We saw our patch of snow here. We rested here for a while. No one really wanted to get up and leave for Bedni. But you know how the Himalayan weather changes. We reluctantly got up and were on our way. The gradual ascent is more of a hilly path, occasionally getting rocky. As we treaded along for a couple of hours or so, the snow covered mountains began showing up at a distance. We could see a trail of snow being blown off the summit. The winds must’ve been strong. “What would it be like if one was stranded in such an environment?”, I thought to myself. As we traced the path downhill, we could see a couple of blue dots. Finally, Bedni Bugyal was in sight!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the trekkers spent the afternoon playing cricket at the camp, and some spent watching it. Me? Shooting, ofcourse. Although I was constraining myself from shooting, I was running really low on batteries. The first thing that I did after reaching Bedni was to find out which direction is South. There was a small hill towards South. I wanted to have another go at shooting the Milky Way that night and this was a better composition. Considering the position of the Milky Way the previous night, it was quite simple to deduce that the galaxy would rise behind the hill around 1 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 4 in the evening, winds picked up and it started raining heavily. Talk about Himalayan weather, eh? I thought my plans for the night will go for a toss. Luckily, the skies cleared up in a couple of hours and all was well. We had dinner (one of the best, I must say!) and some of the trekkers were curious to know more about how to tune the camera to shoot the stars. Well, I can’t say no to a photography gyaan. I spent the next hour explaining how a camera works in simple terms. To put it in practice, they wanted to join me for the night’s shoot. We slept at 9 and woke up at 12, shot till 2 and crawled back into the cozy sleeping bags again. Here’s what we could shoot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_351” align=”aligncenter” width=”660”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/img_4532.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-351&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/img_4532.jpg?w=660&quot; alt=&quot;The Milky Way!&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;990&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Milky Way![/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point in time, my camera battery had completely died out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day 7 | 21st May, 2015 | Bedni Bugyal - Pathar Nachauni&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pathar Nachauni Camp | 13,000ft | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.co.in/maps/place/30%C2%B014&#39;00.7%22N+79%C2%B041&#39;40.3%22E/@30.2335136,79.6945158,766m/data=!3m2!1e3!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x0&quot;&gt;(30.2335136,79.6945158)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Bedni Bugyal, we had to ascend back to the trail. This was a relatively steep ascent compared to the gradual one the previous day. The steep ascent was followed by a gradual one till Pathar Nachauni. To reach the Pathar Nachauni camp, we had to go off track and descend a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we started ascending from Bedni Bugyal, we got to see Bedni kund. This is a small lake with a mandir. I wanted to get a shot of the lake, but my batteries were down. I had put my GoPro to charge overnight. A quick tip, don’t! I ended up losing half the charge on my portable charger, with the GoPro retaining none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_343” align=”aligncenter” width=”660”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/17669196684_c46b5736ed_k.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-343&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/17669196684_c46b5736ed_k.jpg?w=660&quot; alt=&quot;Bedni Kund, on the way to Pathar Nachauni&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bedni Kund, on the way to Pathar Nachauni[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The terrain changes so quickly as we gain altitude in the Himalayas. Into an hour of trekking, the meadows opened up to a rocky terrain. Apparently, it had snowed at higher altitudes the previous night. Luckily, the weather was stable now. As we gained altitude, we could see snow deposited on either side of the path. This was our first encounter with the snow-ridden path and we all were pretty excited. There were some men clearing the trekking path for us ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_346” align=”aligncenter” width=”660”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/17671317713_933fa28c87_k.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-346&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/17671317713_933fa28c87_k.jpg?w=660&quot; alt=&quot;The path to Pathar Nacahauni&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The path to Pathar Nacahauni[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trekking on the snow was harder than I had anticipated. It would’ve probably been easier if it weren’t for my swaying camera bag and a heavy backpack. I moved to the front of the group to shoot the video. I found out the hard way that shooting, balancing and climbing is a tough task. I slipped and fell a couple of times. Mules do not carry the luggage up till Pathar Nachauni. There is a place called Ghora Lautani, which literally translates to “place where horses turn back”. Pathar Nachauni literally translates to ”dancers made of rock”. There is a local legend behind this place which explains the name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we reached Pathar Nachauni around 1 in the afternoon, the winds picked up. During the course of the stay, we realized that this was the windiest camp of them all. But it was a beautiful sight nevertheless, with the tents facing the Kaali Daak mountain. I was feeling more tired than usual, probably because of the rugged sleep the previous two nights. I took a dose of some pain killers, and a diamox as a precaution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After dinner, I casually washed the utensils in the cold water with my bare hands. It felt normal initially, but within a minute, I felt like there were microscopic needles embedded in my palm and they growing in size. I shouted in pain! Trying to warm my hands up quickly was a worse decision. The agitation increased by folds. Gradually allowing the palm to reach room temperature was the best remedy. Excited about the next day’s trek, I had a good night’s sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A piece of advice, never rinse your bare hands with cold water at 9 in the himalayan night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/18291908975_34999c0c3e_k.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-349 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/18291908975_34999c0c3e_k.jpg?w=660&quot; alt=&quot;Nothing beats hot tea in during the cold, windy evenings.&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day 8 | 22nd May, 2015 | Pathar Nachauni - Bhagwabasa&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bhagwabasa Camp | 15,000 ft | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.co.in/maps/place/30%C2%B015&#39;06.6%22N+79%C2%B042&#39;45.0%22E/@30.251835,79.712492,766m/data=!3m2!1e3!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x0&quot;&gt;(30.251835, 79.712492)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a much needed refreshing sleep! The trek would get much more interesting from this point onwards. We had heard that the Bhagwabasa camp was completely on snow! Layers and layers of snow. It was going to be a relatively harder trek for the next couple of days. The trekking path was an ascent till Kalu Vinayak temple and a gradual descent to Bhagwabasa camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were given a facility to deposit a few of the luggage at Pathar Nachauni. Since my camera bag was giving me troubles, I deposited it over there. We were also given snow grippers. Its an elastic addon  with metallic spikes at the bottom. It helps in providing grip while trekking on snow. The trek leaders showed us how to use them and would instruct us to put it on when required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trek up to Kalu Vinayak temple was a hard one. The path was primarily rocky and there was occasional snow along the trekking path. While we were struggling to walk on the snow, I could see some locals running down the slopes of the snow-ridden mountains. “Given enough time, anyone can do anything.”, I thought. By the time we reached Kalu Vinayak temple, I was very disappointed. You’re on a peak. You look around and you see the mighty Himalayan peaks all around you. Wow, what a sight! You look down at your feet, and you’re standing on garbage! Wow (sarcasm), what a sight! Remember the eco bags that we had? I picked up most of the throwaways and deposited them into the eco bag. I highly encourage you to pick up the plastics along your trek path, wherever that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Kalu Vinayak temple, the path was completely covered in snow. The trek leaders instructed us to put on the grippers, and we did. Trust me, it makes a lot of difference! If it weren’t for the grippers, I’m pretty we would’ve skid and fallen off at many points in the trek. After a couple of hours of trekking on the snow, we finally reached Bhagwabasa. And boy, what a beautiful campsite it was!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the fatigue had magically vanished and we were full of enthusiasm. The camp was completely covered in snow. They had laid out tents on top of the snow. The camp was very hygienic. There was absolutely no vegetation. The trees had vanished long back along the trek path. The grass had vanished somewhere along the way to Kalu Vinayak temple. There was no flowing water at all. The organizers literally dug deep into the old snow, heated it up and provided water for us to drink. We were asked to compulsorily get sunglasses, but I hadn’t realized why. The reflection off the snow has a very profound effect on the eye. I couldn’t stay without my sunglasses even for a minute. The higher Himalayas is such a hostile environment. I never thought I’d be burning under sun when there’s snow all around me. There was a special team at the campsite to take us to Roopkund and back the following morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A place right next to the camp was slightly elevated. We used this a slide. People went crazy over it and we started taking turns sliding. Although I wanted to save the charge on my GoPro, I couldn’t resist taking it out again. My DSLR battery was all out! We had some fun shoots with the GoPro and used it for what it’s meant to be used for.. sports. Then came the snow ball fights, followed by hot tea. Ah, good times! Sipping hot tea on a snow covered Himalayan was a different experience altogether. I struck an item off my wishlist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the evening fell, people began clicking pictures. I felt handicapped without a DSLR. A quarter capacity of the portable charger was all that I had left. And I had to save the last for the best. The sunset on this fine evening is something that I can never forget! High altitude Himalayan sunsets are so serene. Now I understand why people get lost in philosophical thoughts. It cannot be explained, it can only be experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_354” align=”aligncenter” width=”660”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/roopkund_bhagwabasa.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-354 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/roopkund_bhagwabasa.jpg?w=660&quot; alt=&quot;Himalayan Sunset at Bhagwabasa&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Himalayan Sunset at Bhagwabasa. Photo Credits: Subramanian M[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I did while I was entering the campsite was to checkout out the composition towards South. Kaali Daak, a snow covered peak, was standing in all it’s might. I could imagine how The Milky Way would be positioned against the mountain. I could imagine how I would compose the image. I knew the exact camera settings that I had to make to get that perfect shot. I knew the exact time that I had to get up to get that shot. The weather was clear and the stage was set!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except that I had no charge on my DSLR left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day 9 | 23rd May, 2015 | Bhagwabasa - Roopkund - Pathar Nachauni&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Roopkund | 15,750 ft | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.co.in/maps/place/30%C2%B015&#39;44.5%22N+79%C2%B043&#39;53.4%22E/@30.262358,79.731487,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x0&quot;&gt;(30.262358, 79.731487)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, our extremely energetic professor and photographer, Subramanian sir, came to my rescue. He had a few spare batteries and lent one to me. I had requested him to join me in the photoshoot that I was planning for the night, and he obliged. We were supposed to start the trek to Roopkund at 4am the next morning. We knew it was going to be hard to shoot and we wouldn’t be getting enough sleep for the next day’s trek. But this is a one-in-a-lifetime opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carrying a tripod, DSLR and lenses all the way to the top along with other necessities was damn hard. Moreover, getting up and stepping out of the tent at 1 in the bone chilling night at higher altitudes wasn’t as easy as I had thought. I took off my gloves to setup the tripod and camera. By the time I was done, I couldn’t feel my fingers due to the cold. All this, after a tiring trek the previous day and more tiring and a sleepless trek up ahead. I set the focus on my lens and pointed my camera towards the Kaali Daak peak. I made some settings and clicked the shutter release. And voilà, this is the image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_347” align=”aligncenter” width=”660”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/18288008532_0de7b4c5a8_k.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-347&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/18288008532_0de7b4c5a8_k.jpg?w=660&quot; alt=&quot;The Grand Galaxy: Milky May, as seen from Bhagwabasa at 12:59 AM on 23rd May, 2015.&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Grand Galaxy: Milky May, as seen from Bhagwabasa at 12:59 AM on 23rd May, 2015.[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to capturing the grand galaxy is to know when and where to shoot. From my previous attempt at Khajjiar lake during December, I figured that the moonless, cloudless nights at a place without light pollution during the peak of the summer is the best time to shoot the Milky Way in the Northern Hemisphere. A lot of stuff just fell in place. Otherwise, it wouldn’t have been possible for me to capture this beauty. Coincidentally, this trek was a perfect match for the requirement. The trek was almost cancelled before it even started. Although I had run out of batteries, Subramanian sir was kind enough to share his spare battery pack. The weather was clear. I must say, I’m very lucky to have captured this image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to the tent at 2:00 in the night. We were supposed to get up at 3:00 and start for Roopkund at 4:00. I was too excited to sleep. I mean, how could one sleep when one of their dreams had just come true? The organizers started waking everyone up at 3:00, and the preparations began. Why were we leaving so early? Snow, ofcourse. It’s easier to trek on hard snow, compared to soft, melting snow. The special team gathered us up and started giving instructions. We were asked to carry flash lights and goggles compulsorily. They insisted a lot on discipline. It plays a very important role in the mountains. We were given some dry fruits to carry along with us. We had formed a line and were waiting for others to join in. The clock was ticking, but there were delays. When it struck 4:00, the special team started leading us forward, leaving others behind. That’s how serious they were about discipline. In about 5 minutes, others caught up. Another 5 minutes down the trek, the organizers realized that some of the trekkers hadn’t got their goggles. Once the sun is up, it’s virtually impossible to trek back to the camp without goggles. They were sent back. Yes, the organizers are very serious about this. Those trekkers went back to the camp and managed to find a pair of goggles and caught up to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, trekking on the hard snow at 4 AM with a flashlight and trekking pole was a thrilling experience! One slip, and you would roll over down the mountain. I was scared to look down at first, but eventually, I got used to it. Trekking pole serves as a third leg while ascending and descending. Without it, it’s virtually impossible to trek, unless you’re exposed to this environment. I wasn’t feeling all that well and energetic. For some reason, I couldn’t even talk clearly. Probably, the lack of sleep the previous night had something to do with it. There was even a point in time during the ascent when I just wanted it to be finished. I was carrying my DSLR and a couple of lenses in my bag as well. This added a lot of extra difficulty. The brain said “Give up!”, heart said “No!”. (and the mouth couldn’t say anything. I couldn’t speak properly, remember?). The path twists and turns, with some crazy ascents. You keep toggling between hill side and valley side trekking. As a typical trekking group, the individual speeds of the trekkers vary a lot. This makes the group spread wide along the trail. The trek leaders did a wonderful job of keeping the team together. However, the downside of this was the long waiting time everytime we regrouped and reorganized. After a long 3 hour trek, we were finally able to see the Roopkund valley at a distance, and there were cheers. After one final push up the steep slope, we had finally made it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/17669292414_e6ddf968cc_k.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-344 size-large aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/17669292414_e6ddf968cc_k.jpg?w=660&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_355” align=”aligncenter” width=”660”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/mg_0206.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-355 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/10/mg_0206.jpg?w=660&quot; alt=&quot;The Team&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Team! Photo Credits: Subramanian M[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We congratulated one another and spent time clicking pictures and shooting videos. It was a moment of rejoice. This is what we had trekked so long and hard for. We didn’t climb down till the frozen lake as it was risky. On the top, I noticed that I hadn’t tied my shoe lace properly. This made the ascent much more tougher. Sadly, we couldn’t see any of the skeletal remains either. That disappointed me a bit, but that’s alright. You can’t have the cake and eat it too. There’s always next time. No one went up to Junargali either, as we were running out of time. I still remember the taste of hot parathas on the top. Yes, one of the guides had actually carried hot parathas till the peak, just for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it was time to bid goodbye to Roopkund. I was the last person to leave the valley, which is pretty obvious because I’m a photographer. The team had moved forward. One of the guides was with me. In other of the steep descents, we had to take a curvy path to descend. The guide just held my hand starting running down the descent in a straight line. I was scared to death! Only then, did I realize the power of the grippers. Had I realized it before, the ascent would’ve been much easier. I was pretty confident from that point onwards and even started running down the mountain further along the trek. The guides informed that it’s all about balance. All we had to do was keep our body vertical, and the rest followed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we were nearing Bhagwabasa, there was a point where we could slide down the mountain. The guides did it first and some trekkers followed. Usually, I’m not the sort who tries these kinda stuff out, but I thought I would give it a try since the guides were around. You’d start sliding down the mountain when one guide pushes you. You should control the speed and direction with your legs. The guides at the bottom will stop you once you reach there. I switched on my GoPro and started sliding. Mid-way, I totally lost control, rotated and started sliding down the mountain head-first with no control over speed! If a couple of guides hadn’t stopped me (one of whom I hurt with the momentum), that video would’ve probably been my last!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, we reached Bhagwabasa camp. We rested there for a while, had lunch and left for Pathar Nachauni. Nothing much interesting (compared to the onward trek atleast) happened over the next trek routes. We reached Pathar Nachauni around 3 in the afternoon. We had tea and spent some time chit chatting over the Roopkund experience. As night fell, we had dinner and curled up in our sleeping bags, with a sense of achievement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day 10 | 24th May, 2015 | Pathar Nachauni - Bedni Bugyal - Ghairoli Patal - Wan village - Lohajung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pathar Nachauni to Wan in a day? They must be crazy!”, I thought. We took 3 days to trek from Wan to Pathar Nachauni. How in the world are we gonna trek from Pathar Nachauni to Wan in a day? I know that it’s a descent, but they’re difficult as well. We left a bit early and went from Pathar Nachauni to Bedni Bugyal. We didn’t stop at Bedni. Apparently, there was a shortcut from Bedni to Ghairoli, which doesn’t pass through Ali Bugyal. We made it to Ghairoli Patal around lunch time. And guess what we had for lunch.. Maggi! Post-lunch, we left for Wan. We spent some time near the Neel Ganga river and I gave a waterproof GoPro a wade inside the water. The water was damn clear! Finally, we reached Wan around 4 in the afternoon, with a great sense of satisfaction and achievement. Some vehicles were waiting for us to take us back to Lohajung Base camp. In the night, the certificates were distributed and a couple of awards were announced; the most eco-friendly trekker and the best trekker, both of which were received by our beloved professor and photographer, Subbu sir. Well deserved indeed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day 11 | 25th May, 2015 | Lohajung - Katgodham&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing much to say here. It was a good scenic ride. All along the way, I kept re-living those amazing moments in the trek. We had a train to Delhi in the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day 12 | 26th May, 2015 | Katgodham - Delhi - Bangalore&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached Delhi in the morning. We took a flight from Delhi to Bangalore at 8:15 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home, Sweet Home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;In a nutshell:
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my hardest and highest trek till date. This 6-day trek in the high altitudes offered a lot of terrains. First, there were dense forests, followed by plain grasslands, rocky terrains, hard snow, soft melting snow and even cement tracks. There were a lot of sleepless nights, slips, falls, fatigue and a good amount of tan. Thanks &lt;a href=&quot;http://indiahikes.in/&quot;&gt;indiahikes.in&lt;/a&gt;, for organizing such an amazing trek. The food was amazing, especially the hot gulab jamun at the highest camp and maggi during the descent. Its virtually impossible to reach roopkund without the help of the local guides. They taught us the tips and tricks of trekking across different terrains and narrated the stories behind the places that we were crossing. The technical team for the last ascent was equally amazing! I managed to get a few snaps that I had been craving since years. Carrying most of my photography equipment to the top was totally worth it! This was also the first time I was shooting with my new GoPro Hero. I managed to capture some amazing videos and I plan to make a travelogue out of it soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the high resolution image set: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/vijeshm/sets/72157651411379514&quot;&gt;https://www.flickr.com/photos/vijeshm/sets/72157651411379514&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trip Duration:&lt;/strong&gt; 8 Days, 9 Nights (from Delhi to Delhi, excluding our Nainital detour)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel Arrangements:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://indiahikes.in/&quot;&gt;Indiahikes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://roopkund.com&quot;&gt;Roopkund.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trekking Equipment:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decathlon.in/&quot;&gt;Decathlon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Approximate Cost: (pick those relevant to you and sum it up)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Flight ticket (Bangalore to Delhi and back): ₹10,000&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Train Ticket (Delhi to Katgodham and back): ₹1,500&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Trek Registration: ₹10,500&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Trekking equipment (Rucksack, Trekking shoes, Jacket, Thermals, Gloves, Goggles, Trekking pole): ₹16,000 - ₹18,000
Do keep in mind that this is a one-time investment.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Miscellaneous: ₹2,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best time to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; May - October&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 01:47:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://sanchaara.in/adventure/ali%20bugyal/bedni%20bugyal/bhagwabasa/ghairoli%20patal/india/lohajung/milky%20way/mystery%20lake/nainital/pathar%20nachauni/photography/roopkund/trekking/uttarakhand/2015/10/04/roopkund-the-mystery-lake/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sanchaara.in/adventure/ali%20bugyal/bedni%20bugyal/bhagwabasa/ghairoli%20patal/india/lohajung/milky%20way/mystery%20lake/nainital/pathar%20nachauni/photography/roopkund/trekking/uttarakhand/2015/10/04/roopkund-the-mystery-lake/</guid>
        
        
        <category>adventure</category>
        
        <category>ali bugyal</category>
        
        <category>bedni bugyal</category>
        
        <category>bhagwabasa</category>
        
        <category>ghairoli patal</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>lohajung</category>
        
        <category>milky way</category>
        
        <category>mystery lake</category>
        
        <category>nainital</category>
        
        <category>pathar nachauni</category>
        
        <category>photography</category>
        
        <category>roopkund</category>
        
        <category>trekking</category>
        
        <category>uttarakhand</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let us go on a road trip.. Now!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are one of the them who has watched the beautiful sunrise at Nandi hills, consider yourself lucky! Nothing is more beautiful than perching on a hill and watching the sun rise. Every sun shine brings in hope :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_322” align=”alignnone” width=”653”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/sunrise-at-nandi-hills.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-322&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/sunrise-at-nandi-hills.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo Courtesy :&quot; width=&quot;653&quot; height=&quot;490&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photo Courtesy :[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hate being late, but we are so good at it ;) We missed the beautiful sunrise, but the nature was in mood to treat us with something special that day.. We started around 6 in the morning and the drive was pleasant. Driving along the zig zag roads and the hair pin curves was fun :D We could see a lot of people cycling back. Probably they were one of the lucky ones ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06184.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-323&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06184.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06184&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Nandi Hills&lt;/b&gt; or &lt;b&gt;Nandidurg&lt;/b&gt;  is an ancient hill fortress in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chikkaballapur_district&quot;&gt;Chikkaballapur district&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karnataka&quot;&gt;Karnataka&lt;/a&gt;. It is 10 km from Chickballapur town and approximately 60 km from the city of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bengaluru&quot;&gt;Bengaluru&lt;/a&gt;. The hills are nestled near the town of Nandi. [source-wiki].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were welcomed by a huge arched fort entrance, where the ticket counter is. All vehicles have to be parked a little further from this entrance. If you are planning to carry any food items up the hills, get ready to negotiate with the monkeys! The monkeys here are super smart! We were hungry and planned to munch on something inside the car at the parking space. It just took two minutes for the smarties to notice this and call a bunch of others to raid us. Within no time there were monkeys all over the car, trying to figure out how to get into the car. One of the monkeys was jumping on the bonnet hoping to find a magical entrance. We then had to pack all the food stuffs back into a bag and slowly move the car to a different parking space. Even as we got down the car, few of the monkeys were still giving us evil looks :P There are beautiful tree houses near the parking space. Everyone around were busy getting photos clicked at this spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06187.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-324&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06187.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06187&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06193.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-325&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06193.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06193&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of temples here. As you walk up the hill you will love and hate the wind at the same time. The fierce wind blowing into your face gives some freaking awesome vibes to ask for more of it!! You asked for a break from monotony, and here you have it :D The experience is amazing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06237.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-326&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06237.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06237&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another famous spot here is the Tipu drop. Supposedly the spot where Tipu used to execute the unlawful. As we watched the curled up roads from this spot, the wind got more fierce. The view was amazing, but we could hardly hold ourselves against the wind, and we slowly moved back to the gate. This demanded a hot cup of coffee. There is a nandini parlour near the parking space, which serves the perfect blend of coffee. We relaxed here for a while as we discussed what next..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06262.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-327&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06262.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06262&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Little do people know about the birthplace of Vishveshvaraya - Muddenahalli, which is about 15kms from Nandi hills. The museum here has a large collections of Sir MV’s photographs, writings and some rare belongings. Beside the museum is the ancestral home which is the birthplace of Sir MV. At walkable distance from this place is the samadhi park. The whole environment around here instills an inspiring feeling. We unanimously felt the same while going through the belongings and the writings in the museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06280.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-328&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06280.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06280&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06272.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-329&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06272.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06272&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06271.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-330&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc06271.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06271&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then started our drive back to bangalore. The trip ended with a sumptuous lunch :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tips : Do not miss on the fresh grapes and jackfruits sold by the locals in and around Chikballapur :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 20:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://sanchaara.in/uncategorized/2015/07/30/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sanchaara.in/uncategorized/2015/07/30/</guid>
        
        
        <category>uncategorized</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>And then I realised - We were making memories.. :)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the ones who have been with us since the beginning, from where we started blogging in Sanchaara way back in 2013, you would have followed us on a range of experiences from way down south - Pondi to the foothill of Himalayas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never lose an opportunity to see anything beautiful! Over these years this bunch of friends have ignited the wanderlust in me. And rightly said, Journey is best measured in friends than miles. At a point where we were about to take a detour..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I get more nostalgic, let me digress here..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided on heading to Wayanad. Monsoon is the time to be in God’s own country! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike our previous trips, this time we did not plan much. We hit the road at around 12 late night, and took the Bangalore - Mysore - Gundulpet - Munthanga - Sulthan Bathery route. We reached the Bandipur forest check-post around 4 in the morning and waited until the gates opened at 6. Bandipur, located in Chamarajanagar district of Karnataka forms the heart of dense forest of the Western Ghats along with three other adjoining national parks - Nagarhole, Madhumalai and Wayanad Wildlife sanctuary. The road en route to Wayanad is picturesque with lush green trees. We could spot few wildlife on our way. A happy monsoon invited us, as we got down the cab with umbrellas open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/rain.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-314&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/rain.png?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;499&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sulthan Bathery being the commercial hub in Wayanad, is the best place to stay. We freshened up and headed towards our first stop - Eddkal caves. There is a short trek along the finely laid steps up the Ambukuthi hills to reach the caves. After clicking some photographs, and smiling at the tourists around who were all excited and equally drenched in rain, we reached the top and the monsoon view from there was amazing! Inside the caves there are huge split rocks, ancient stone scripts and pictorial wall inscriptions. An official guide there, explained us with pleasure the history of the place. We spent some time enjoying the beauty of the caves. On our way back we munched on some yummy homemade chocolates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc_0080.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-319&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/dsc_0080.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_0080&quot; width=&quot;683&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next stop - Banasura sagar dam. We were tricked by google maps to take the most un-convenient route to this place. Phew! The roads we took were so narrow and we were almost lost! After dodging against the edges of the narrow roads, we reached the dam. A short walk took us to a serene location which looked like the best strokes with water paint colors. The view of the sunshine filtering through the clouds across the landscape was one of the most beautiful view we had ever seen. We pretty much spent the rest of the day staring at this view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/img_20150718_164002794_1437378970938.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-335&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/img_20150718_164002794_1437378970938.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_20150718_164002794_1437378970938&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;421&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got back to the hotel in Sulthan Bathery at around 8 in the evening. No trip is complete without crazy night-outs. Bye bye to mafia :P This time we had a new game! - &amp;lt;insert-game-name&amp;gt;. One hell of a crazy game. The rules are simple. examples -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like always, we all woke up late the next morning. We hadn’t planned on any sunrise view points, as we were 100% sure of starting late. Next stop was - Jain temple, Sulthan Bathery. This is one of the famous tourist places in Wayanad. The town derives the name from from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tipu_Sultan&quot;&gt;Tipu Sultan&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mysore&quot;&gt;Mysore&lt;/a&gt; who killed all the Jain Monks and used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jainism_in_Kerala&quot;&gt;Jain&lt;/a&gt; temple as his battery here in the 18th century, hence the name Sultan’s Battery. [source-wiki]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_317” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/jain_temple_sulthan_battery.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-317&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/jain_temple_sulthan_battery.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;Photo courtesy : wiki&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;528&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photo courtesy : wiki[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holiday in Kerala is incomplete without a visit to any luscious waterfalls. There are plenty of small and large streams famous in Kerala, and we chose on visiting Kanthampara falls. As we drove closer to the waterfalls we imagined ourselves walking through a picturesque forest.. With the rushing sound of the waterfall in the background and that we would arrive at the base of the waterfalls and look up at the water gushing through the rocks.. Oh stop! The main entry point to the waterfalls was closed :/ Since it was the peak of monsoon, we could only stand by one of the alternate entry points and watch the water flow in rage. It was pretty disappointing! But the refreshingly beautiful view of the tea plantation on our way back to the main city made up for all the loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/img_6251.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-318&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2015/07/img_6251.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_6251&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same night we headed back to Bangalore. Endless talks, laughter, stupid fights, scary stories, music, pulling-leg, rain, food, coffee.. The trip was fun! :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;insert-the-video-clip-here&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;
.. And then I realized - We were making memories.. :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 15:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://sanchaara.in/uncategorized/2015/07/29/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sanchaara.in/uncategorized/2015/07/29/</guid>
        
        
        <category>uncategorized</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Colorado - I found my Western Ghats in U.S!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The very first driving factor that strengthened my decision of doing Masters in US was the idea of travelling in a foreign country and explore new places. Sure, I would have done that otherwise too. But living here and exploring the country as a resident is a whole lot of different experience. When I first got here, everything seemed so organized. The lanes, neatly groomed bushes, paved paths without the traces of soil on them, neatly maintained lush green lawns - all of this was “different” for me. I missed the chaos of my motherland. I missed the rawness of the nature. The smell of the soil, the rocky paths, the crowd, the tender fragrance of the flowers, the warmth of the tea in the rain under the misty western ghats watching the stall person frying out the hot pakodas from the oil - I missed all of it and I thought I would miss it for a long time. But Colorado made me feel at home. It made me fall in love with the mountains here, taught me that being organised is not that bad after all, the smell in the air brought a sense of comfort. The travel bud in me had found its nourishment. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My extended Sancharaa family here at U.S, planned for a much needed break. We were sure that we wanted to visit a scenic place and Colorado topped the list. Planning for a trip in a foreign land was my first experience and quite an exciting one. For us students, money was another factor. We had to carefully plan the trip so as to keep our expenses low. The budget was decided. 300$ it was!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We booked a flight in Spirit airlines(Cheapest domestic flight here). We were 7 in number and Spirit doesn’t allow cabin baggage without paying for it. 25$ per bag :O Instead we booked 2 check-in baggage and it was around 7$ per head. Jugaad works! Money saved is money earned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next challenge was the accommodation. Since it’s a tourist place, the hotels/lodges were no less than 140$ per night per room that could accommodate 4 members. Seemed unrealistic. We looked for other options and we were blessed with &lt;strong&gt;AirBnB -&lt;/strong&gt; ”Find hosts with extra rooms, entire homes, and unique accommodations like castles and igloos”. I think you now have a fair idea about what they do. They have localhosts(no pun intended) around the country who have extra rooms/entire place to rent out for a day/week/month. The homes are fully furnished and have basic amenities. Food was no more a problem. On the way from Denver airport to our first accommodation, we stopped by Walmart and India bazaar and got some frozen parathas, ready-to-eats, eggs, milk, cereals. We were all set for the trip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”” align=”aligncenter” width=”500”]&lt;img src=&quot;https://scontent-dfw1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpt1/v/t1.0-9/11377127_905936412786085_1920616156951251368_n.jpg?oh=f274ce4e9602d3e6a0f67019d1e65a6e&amp;amp;oe=564EFFB8&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; /&gt; AirBnB accommodation at Colorado Springs[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, I will list out the itinerary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 0:&lt;/strong&gt; Driving down to Colorado will be awesome if you stay somewhere close by. I would recommend you to take flight in case if the drive is more than 4 hours because there is SO much to do once you get there.
&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quick tip&lt;/em&gt;: Take a flight to Denver and then drive to Colorado Springs. It’ll save you a lot of money.&lt;/em&gt;
Renting a car has never been this easy (Enterprise). Once you land, find an exit to rental cars’ shuttle service. Keep your Driver’s license and confirmation number ready. 15 minutes and you are done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Mt. Cutler trail + Helen hunt falls + Garden of gods.
&lt;strong&gt;Mt. Cutler trail (6800ft):&lt;/strong&gt; A beautiful 1 mile trail leading you to the top of the peak. Await a breathtaking view of the Colorado springs. Spot seven falls on the way to the peak top. Hike difficulty: Moderate (1.5 hour)
&lt;strong&gt;Helen hunt falls:&lt;/strong&gt; A beautiful waterfalls. Hike for 1 mile to get to the head of the falls. Water is fierce and be careful. (1 hour)
&lt;strong&gt;Garden of Gods:&lt;/strong&gt; Gigantic orange rock formations. Look out for the board to know what you have to look for. “Kissing camels” is one of the prominent one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”” align=”aligncenter” width=”500”]&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent-dfw1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xtp1/t31.0-8/11270549_905933186119741_5899352501735663422_o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; /&gt; Mount Cutler![/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”” align=”alignnone” width=”700”]&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent-dfw1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xat1/v/t1.0-9/10690113_905935772786149_407092308354747879_n.jpg?oh=2e68eefe9076774a88116d4459acf6ec&amp;amp;oe=564CD021&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;575&quot; /&gt; Seven falls view from Mt. Cutler.[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[googlemaps https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m30!1m8!1m3!1d99443.59168784555!2d-104.9366001!3d38.8413404!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!4m19!3e0!4m5!1s0x87135b6f78eaa07b%3A0xc38d0318721780b5!2sMt+Cutler%2C+Colorado+80906%2C+USA!3m2!1d38.7877686!2d-104.8774737!4m5!1s0x87135b9a1abfc81f%3A0x7141172c3c7f1fb0!2sHelen+Hunt+Falls%2C+Colorado%2C+USA!3m2!1d38.7886011!2d-104.9030296!4m5!1s0x87134fd62001d1d1%3A0x1ccc979c5c032b82!2sGarden+of+the+Gods+Rd%2C+Colorado+Springs%2C+CO%2C+USA!3m2!1d38.8964802!2d-104.8481444!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sin!4v1437976055148&amp;amp;w=600&amp;amp;h=450]&lt;strong&gt;Day 2: &lt;/strong&gt;Pikes peak(8$ entry fee for a group of 7 or more) + Drive to Silverthorne
A 21 mile drive to the hill top. The sight of snow capped mountains makes you want to go there even more. While it is summer in the rest of the world, you get to beat the heat at Colorado. Make sure you carry your shades. The super bright white snow can actually get a little irritating after a while. At the 13th mile, there is a small store and a coffee shop. Sipping hot chocolate while feeling the cold breeze was an experience no less than drinking hot tea in misty cold Western Ghats. Nature has its own little ways to remind you of home in a foreign land. Quite an artist, isn’t it?! :) We spend about 3 hours here and then drove to Silverthorne. Just when you think that it can’t get any more beautiful, you land in a place which leaves you in awe. All you want to do is watch out of the window and sink it all in, enough for a lifetime. We reached Silverthorne and stayed at our second accommodation. Sitting by the fireplace, chit-chatting about random things and looking at the snow fall - that’s how our night ended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent-dfw1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xtp1/v/t1.0-9/1551714_905936496119410_792222485228795984_n.jpg?oh=150eabbb00af92218edd85d4a8c86f65&amp;amp;oe=5647A9B2&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; Pikes peak!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 3: &lt;/strong&gt;Drive to Glenwood Springs + Hanging Lake
All geared up for the next destination. Although we had a good night’s sleep, we still missed that “5 minutes” of sleep. It was a 90 mile drive to the Hanging Lake. All of us had decided that we would take a nap in the car. The journey started. Trust me when I say this - We couldn’t close our eyes for a moment! The entire drive was so beautiful. It was like a painting and we were wanderers who wanted to get lost in the colors of Mother Nature. The Glenwood’s grand canyon is something to look for. Makes you feel like tiny creatures in front of the gigantic rock formations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”” align=”alignnone” width=”900”]&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent-dfw1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpt1/t31.0-8/11241439_905935426119517_2676660351431589317_o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;534&quot; /&gt; Hanging Lake[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”” align=”alignnone” width=”900”]&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent-dfw1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xta1/t31.0-8/11263077_905933292786397_888726624152853819_o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;534&quot; /&gt; The hike trail to the top of the waterfalls.[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached our destination after a breathtaking 90-mile drive. Hanging Lake. It started drizzling as if it were to welcome us. What we expected was a beautiful waterfall. What we got was a 1.5 mile difficult hike to the falls. A waterfall on a mountain?! Mindf**cked :D We were more excited now. The rocky path made the hike real difficult. The rain made it worse. We wore our winter jackets to keep us warm. But then, who knew we would sweat during the hike. Who knew that though the distance was 1.5 mile, the elevation was crazy. Who knew that the mushy mud path was enough to trick us into falling down. I had found my chaos, the rawness, the smell of the soil - all that I had missed, the one that I had been longing for - Western Ghats! :’)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”” align=”alignnone” width=”900”]&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent-dfw1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xta1/t31.0-8/11257187_905932506119809_5891741994823640745_o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;599&quot; /&gt; A scene which is etched in my memory forever - on the way from Pikes peak to Silverthorne.[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent-dfw1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xtf1/t31.0-8/11128325_905937192786007_5446523207398022479_o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;1260&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trip duration: &lt;/strong&gt;3 days, 3 nights
&lt;strong&gt;Travel distance:&lt;/strong&gt; 500miles on road.
&lt;strong&gt;Approx cost: &lt;/strong&gt; 96$(Flight roundtrip) + 60$(Accommodation) + 80$(Car and fuel) + 40$(Food) + 40$(Misc) ~ 300$
&lt;strong&gt;Best time to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; May – August
[googlemaps https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m70!1m12!1m3!1d1581447.199599638!2d-107.20677965318495!3d39.27091959633491!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!4m55!3e0!4m5!1s0x876b80aa231f17cf%3A0x118ef4f8278a36d6!2sDenver%2C+CO%2C+United+States!3m2!1d39.739235799999996!2d-104.990251!4m5!1s0x87135b6f78eaa07b%3A0xc38d0318721780b5!2sMt+Cutler%2C+Colorado+80906%2C+USA!3m2!1d38.7877686!2d-104.8774737!4m5!1s0x87135b9a1abfc81f%3A0x7141172c3c7f1fb0!2sHelen+Hunt+Falls%2C+Colorado%2C+USA!3m2!1d38.7886011!2d-104.9030296!4m5!1s0x87135066cc0790ff%3A0x36dbc21ae7596b3a!2sGarden+of+The+Gods+Visitor+%26+Nature+Center%2C+North+30th+Street%2C+Colorado+Springs%2C+CO%2C+USA!3m2!1d38.8738411!2d-104.88666409999999!4m5!1s0x87135a870cbabcbb%3A0x3f1b5171e9cf33db!2sPikes+Peak%2C+Colorado%2C+USA!3m2!1d38.839991999999995!2d-105.043888!4m5!1s0x876a5cb86b1d4285%3A0xee63350e2b758bb8!2sSilverthorne%2C+CO%2C+USA!3m2!1d39.6296191!2d-106.07129409999999!4m5!1s0x8741a3e700378bf1%3A0xf7657a23c5991b92!2sHanging+Lake%2C+Interstate+70%2C+Glenwood+Springs%2C+CO%2C+United+States!3m2!1d39.601391799999995!2d-107.1917206!4m5!1s0x876a5bf671b3d81b%3A0xf52a4a12a6d3243b!2sDillon+Reservoir%2C+Summit+County%2C+CO%2C+United+States!3m2!1d39.609225599999995!2d-106.0610787!4m5!1s0x876ba9ca85fb4895%3A0xefa49d55b6cbb1b1!2sMount+Evans%2C+Clear+Creek+County%2C+CO%2C+United+States!3m2!1d39.588300499999995!2d-105.64382859999999!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sin!4v1438096184942&amp;amp;w=400&amp;amp;h=300]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 11:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://sanchaara.in/colorado/colorado%20springs/uncategorized/2015/07/27/colorado-i-found-my-western-ghats-in-u-s/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sanchaara.in/colorado/colorado%20springs/uncategorized/2015/07/27/colorado-i-found-my-western-ghats-in-u-s/</guid>
        
        
        <category>colorado</category>
        
        <category>colorado springs</category>
        
        <category>uncategorized</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mediator Features</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;mediator-formats-and-css-features&quot;&gt;Mediator Formats and CSS features&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples for different formats and css features&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;header-formats&quot;&gt;Header Formats&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Header1
##Header2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;blockquotes&quot;&gt;Blockquotes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consetetur sadipscing elitr, sed diam nonumy eirmod tempor invidunt ut labore et dolore magna aliquyam erat, sed diam voluptua. At vero eos et accusam et justo duo dolores et ea rebum. Stet clita kasd gubergren, no sea takimata sanctus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##orderd lists
1. one
2. two
3. three&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unorderd-lists&quot;&gt;unorderd lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apple&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Banana&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;links&quot;&gt;Links&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://example.com/&quot; title=&quot;With a Title&quot;&gt;example link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;combinations&quot;&gt;Combinations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consetetur sadipscing elitr, sed diam nonumy eirmod tempor invidunt ut labore et dolore magna aliquyam erat, sed diam voluptua. At vero eos et accusam et justo duo dolores et ea rebum. Stet clita kasd gubergren, no sea takimata sanctus&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Apple&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Banana&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Plum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 06:34:25 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://sanchaara.in/mediator/feature/2014/11/30/mediator_features/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sanchaara.in/mediator/feature/2014/11/30/mediator_features/</guid>
        
        <category>featured</category>
        
        
        <category>mediator</category>
        
        <category>feature</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sancharaa goes international! This time its Chicago :D</title>
        <description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;With more than half the sancharaa team in India, I was feeling pretty lonely. I guess someone up there sensed my loneliness, one of them got an opportunity to fly to US :D There was no looking back. The 4 of us decided on where could we meet, coordinated with the date, timings and place. Within a span of one hour, tickets were booked. One was supposed to fly from New York and the other two from Dallas to meet a friend in Chicago. :D And all this happened over Google Hangouts. Technology strikes again! Noticed something different from the rest of our other trips?! Yeah, that&#39;s right. There was NO PLANNING! It was totally dynamic. Probably it was the joy of meeting my friend after a year and a half that did not let me think twice about the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nov 7th.&lt;/strong&gt;
The day finally arrived. Boarded the plane. It was 2 and half hour journey. I looked out of the window and the view was breathtaking. Vijay had come to pick us up. It had been a year and a half and I still shared the same comfort level. Probably that&#39;s the beauty of friendship. The feeling of being in Chicago slowly sunk in and oh boy! that felt awesome. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_259” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_7597.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-259&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_7597.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;Welcome to Chicago!&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Welcome to Chicago![/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;We started with Cloud gate, affectionately called &quot;The Bean&quot;. The Bean is the main tourist attraction present in the Millennium park. It is famous for the way it looks and its extremely polished exterior that reflects the city&#39;s skyline. It is beautiful to look into it and make faces. :D Luckily, we even got to attend a RedBull Can Art Exhibition and sip a free redbull ;)  We walked in the Millenium street and got back home. That was the end of the first day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-265&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/10422103_805506786162382_7820090455993889275_n.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;10422103_805506786162382_7820090455993889275_n&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;530&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”” align=”aligncenter” width=”741”]&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/pushbullet-uploads/ujBzpr2i0qq-sTChdDWliFYPi6Hqq4fc3kD9ys7ch2OY/IMG_20141107_144634.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;741&quot; height=&quot;526&quot; /&gt; Guess what’s it made from. The Bull from the Redbull![/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
Nov 8th.&lt;/strong&gt;
After spending an awesome time at I-wont-mention-where-because-that’s-our-next-blog-post, our hero was here in Chicago to explore with us :D The four of us set out on our very first spot, the &lt;strong&gt;Shedd Aquarium&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;drum rolls&lt;/em&gt; :D It is not just another aquarium. It is a whole different world. It is mesmerizing. It is vast. It is beautiful! :) You get to see turtles, piranhas, Beluga whales, dolphins, seal, corals, anemones and a hundred sub-species of that. My favorite were the Jelly fishes. They are venomous, yet so beautiful. Their movement is so mesmerizing that you can’t take your eyes off them. One more favorite Do not miss the Dolphin and Seal’s show. The show is called One World! They are just adorable. Bottomline - Shedd is an ecosystem in itself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”” align=”aligncenter” width=”340” class=” “]&lt;img src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/B19HtzaIAAArqIV.jpg:small&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;340&quot; height=&quot;340&quot; /&gt; Jelly fish[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nov 9th.&lt;/strong&gt;
Field museum and Adler Planetarium.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_7968.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-261&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_7968.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_7968&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_7944.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-262&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_7944.jpg?w=683&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_7944&quot; width=&quot;683&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_7909.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-263&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_7909.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_7909&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skydeck Chicago.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are taken to 103rd floor of a building in a lightning speed lift. The pressure difference starts acting upon you. You have pain in your ears. The lift stops. “Freedom” is the word you utter! You step out of the lift, look through the crystal clear glass windows and there are you are, standing, witnessing the beauty of an urban city, fully lit majestic buildings, neatly arranged glittering like gold pearls. Look down and you can see a number of fireflies look-alikes - yes, that’s right! Cars moving around. Man has indeed been successful in making man-made structures look beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_258” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_8139.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-258 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_8139.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_8139&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; That’s the Willis tower[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_264” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_8050.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-264 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_8050.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_8050&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; View from 101th floor.[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little more on Chicago life…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The make of the city - Chicago popularly known as “City of lights” is rightly called so. The downtown is a lively place with lots of tourists flowing in. This place is an amalgamation of new and old buildings. If the new ones showcase a lot of glass-built buildings, the old ones highlight the heritage of the city. At every intersection of 2 roads, at least one of the corner will have a Starbucks. Probably that is why 1 in 2 people will have a coffee cup in their hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public transport - Chicago has an awesome public transport. The subways are really helpful. Pay once, and you can reach your destination no matter how many times you change lines. By “Lines” I mean, different routes. Each of these lines are color coded and run in a specific predefined route. Each station has a ticket vending machine. You can swipe your card or put in cash to buy tickets. There are passes as well. These passes let you travel either in bus or the train. How cool is that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People - They are considerate. They have a smile on their faces. If you are trying to click a selfie, there are people who come and offer to click a pic of yours. This happened to us over 10-12 times. So yeah! they are definitely sweet. Although look out for rash drivers. You might almost lose your life :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weather - Extremely chilly during winters. The winds make it worse. Make sure you have covered yourself up if you plan to go in winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tips:
If you are in Chicago for 4-5 days and plan to cover most of the famous places, it is better to buy a City pass which costs around 90$. Without this, it costs almost double of this. Plus this pass ensures VIP entry to every place. This way, you don’t have to wait in long queues.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_8278.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-260&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_8278.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_8278&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take subways to travel. It is called &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chicago Transit Authority&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Renting a car is not necessary. All the tourist attractions are 5 minutes walk from each other. Even otherwise, you can take subways to connect to each other. They are comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_8227.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-257&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/img_8227.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_8227&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trip duration: &lt;/strong&gt;3 days, 2 nights
&lt;strong&gt;Travel distance:&lt;/strong&gt; 1000km (approx) for the complete journey
&lt;strong&gt;Approx cost: &lt;/strong&gt; 150$ + Flight charges + Accommodation(We stayed at our friend’s apartment)
&lt;strong&gt;Best time to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; May - November&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_269” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/10632599_863153387028531_9161720852416338599_n.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-269&quot; src=&quot;https://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/10632599_863153387028531_9161720852416338599_n.jpg?w=750&quot; alt=&quot;...and that&#39;s the sancharaa team! :) &quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; …and that’s the sancharaa team! :)[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shedd Aquarium - Field museum - Adler planetarium&lt;/strong&gt;
[googlemaps https://maps.google.co.in/maps?sll=41.8668185,-87.6165056&amp;amp;amp;sspn=0.0122723,0.0219729&amp;amp;amp;geocode=FTXZfgIdqh3H-in5dbdfYysOiDHf-1Df450FMg%3BFRXUfgIdLBLH-ilXQDAzfSsOiDHax35fRyAStQ%3BFV3UfgIdATrH-im1FLG3bysOiDGmjiESqqMgaQ&amp;amp;amp;saddr=Shedd+Aquarium,+1200+S+Lake+Shore+Dr,+Chicago,+IL+60605,+United+States&amp;amp;amp;daddr=The+Field+Museum,+1400+S+Lake+Shore+Dr,+Chicago,+IL+60605,+United+States+to:Adler+Planetarium,+1300+S+Lake+Shore+Dr,+Chicago,+IL+60605,+United+States&amp;amp;amp;dirflg=w&amp;amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;amp;ll=41.866811,-87.61142&amp;amp;amp;spn=0.001614,0.008023&amp;amp;amp;output=embed&amp;amp;w=425&amp;amp;h=350]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;360 Chicago - Cloud gate - Skydeck Chicago&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[googlemaps https://maps.google.co.in/maps?f=d&amp;amp;amp;source=s_d&amp;amp;amp;saddr=360+Chicago,+North+Michigan+Avenue,+Chicago,+IL,+United+States&amp;amp;amp;daddr=Cloud+Gate,+Chicago,+IL,+United+States+to:Skydeck+Chicago,+South+Wacker+Drive,+Chicago,+IL,+United+States&amp;amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;amp;geocode=FQ4pfwIdO_LG-im3DEPhriwOiDEjCS11jgL0Pw%3BFSEUfwIdePnG-iFRSjrO7z9NBin1KzOHpiwOiDFRSjrO7z9NBg%3BFUQFfwIdl8fG-iH91EUJfzAJzym7-2niviwOiDH91EUJfzAJzw&amp;amp;amp;aq=0&amp;amp;amp;oq=360&amp;amp;amp;sll=41.883027,-87.629306&amp;amp;amp;sspn=0.017733,0.039482&amp;amp;amp;dirflg=w&amp;amp;amp;mra=ps&amp;amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;amp;ll=41.883027,-87.629306&amp;amp;amp;spn=0.017733,0.039482&amp;amp;amp;output=embed&amp;amp;w=425&amp;amp;h=350]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 04:29:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://sanchaara.in/chicago/uncategorized/2014/11/13/chicago/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sanchaara.in/chicago/uncategorized/2014/11/13/chicago/</guid>
        
        
        <category>chicago</category>
        
        <category>uncategorized</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve --watch&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-help&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s dedicated Help repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot; data-lang=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;footer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;site-footer&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;subscribe&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;/feed.xml&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;span&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;tooltip&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;fa fa-rss&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;/i&amp;gt; Subscribe!&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;inner&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;All&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;copyright&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;mailto:me@sandeepraju.in&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Team&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Sanchaara&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;amp;copy; 2017 &amp;amp;bull; All rights reserved.&amp;lt;/section&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;poweredby&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Made&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;http://jekyllrb.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/section&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;/footer&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 07:34:25 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://sanchaara.in/jekyll/update/2014/08/29/welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sanchaara.in/jekyll/update/2014/08/29/welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
        
        <category>featured</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A pinch of panic with lots of adventure amidst the Western Ghats</title>
        <description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;It was 10:00 pm. The busy Bangalore was slowing down and gradually drifting towards sleep unlike the Hebbal flyover infront of us which is always busy with airport taxi’s and transport vehicles. Sandeep and myself were eagerly waiting for the beginning of our next trip(after chikamagalur). Our mobile phones were continuously beeping with WhatsApp messages like “ಮಗ ಎಲ್ಲಿದಿರೊ”(Guys where are you?) as we were expecting a ride from a hired TT (Tempo traveler.. :P) which of course had already picked up most of the crazy people of our gang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;Finally after picking us and Mahesh, the journey began. Journey to where? A place in the western ghats - “Dandeli”. A big thanks to the Google navigation app which was constantly showing us the directions in the dreadful midnight to Dandeli although at some places it told us to take a right turn when there was no place to turn at all. It was around 6:00 in the morning when each of us started to wake up one by one. The moment we turned towards the window we could see our TT riding on a road with forests on either sides. A typical countryside view made us happy, reminding us that we were now away from traffic signals and concrete forest.&lt;span style=&quot;line-height:1.5em;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;We reached Dandeli around 7:30 in the morning where our traveling agent had arranged for a guide vehicle from Dandeli town to Pradhani, a small village. In Pradhani, we stayed at Dandeli Jungle camp. Because of the overnight journey we all were really tired and craving for a good breakfast. But the breakfast was still not ready. We got 4 rooms in the camp and we split ourselves into four groups. We quickly refreshed and moved towards to the dining area. Hot upma, omelette, bread-butter-jam, coffee and tea was something which we needed to get going. After hogging, we were all set to start the Dandeli extravaganza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_222” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_4094.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-222&quot; alt=&quot;Breakfast at jungle camp&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_4094.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Breakfast at jungle camp[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_221” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_4090.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-221&quot; alt=&quot;Stay at jungle camp&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_4090.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Stay at jungle camp[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;The first plan was to visit Syntheri Rocks, a natural rock formation by the river. The only means of transport to the place were the local jeeps because of the muddy roads. We had to wait for sometime for a local jeep to take us there. In the meantime we decided to just walk around the jungle camp and we didn&#39;t regret. We came across a dry paddy field in which a woman was husking. A rare scene in the city side, isn&#39;t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_223” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_4103.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-223&quot; alt=&quot;Removing husk in paddy field&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_4103.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Husking in paddy field[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;Finally our jeep arrived to the jungle camp and we hurriedly boarded the jeep as we were very excited to visit Syntheri rocks. The jeep started to move in the midst of dense thick forests and we were welcomed by a couple of wild animals like baboons and wild eagles. After 60 minutes of amazing forest journey we arrived at Syntheri rocks. The view of Syntheri rocks became clear gradually as we stepped down the rocky stairs one by one and the view of the majestic rocks - you bet it was breathtaking. The hard mountain rocks were carved to be beautiful stones by the chilling water drifting between the mountain spaces. We wished if could have seen this beauty in rainy season when the river will be full. But anyone visiting this place must be very careful as the stone surfaces are very smooth due to continuously flowing river. If you fall to water accidentally then the chance of survival is too less…meaning…&quot;COMPLETE  ಹೊಗೆ&quot; :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_224” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_4119.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-224&quot; alt=&quot;The jeep ride to Syntheri&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_4119.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The jeep ride to Syntheri[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_225” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_4134.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-225&quot; alt=&quot;Steps to Syntheri rocks&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_4134.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Steps to Syntheri rocks[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_226” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_4135.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-226&quot; alt=&quot;The Spectacular Syntheri&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_4135.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Spectacular Syntheri[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;After Syntheri, we came back to jungle camp for a munchy lunch. The lunch was better than breakfast and there was only veg food. After hogging we are ready for the next big thing...WATER SPORTS...hurrah! Since Dandeli jungle camp doesn&#39;t have any water sports they took us to Bison resort by a jeep again. There, people were already having fun.. Kayaking, natural Jacuzzi bath and Coracle rides! Oh.. By the way, the river we spoke about all this time is River Kali. We decided to do only Kayaking and Natural Jacuzzi bath as the Coracle ride wasn&#39;t worth(The water sports + to and fro travel to resort costed us Rs. 500). There were kayaking boats for both single and pair rowers. Kayaking was really an amazing experience. Sailing a short flat boat(Kayak) by using a double-bladed paddle is not so simple as it appears. You can either choose to sail in peace enjoying the lush greenery on either sides of the river or you can choose to make some noise which will scare the hell out of birds living in the trees. I remember one of my friend screaming &quot;I am happy, I am happy&quot;. Hey wait, I don’t know swimming, what if the boat flips over!? No worries.. life jacket and life guards to the rescue. Your rescue mission will be pakka accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_217” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_0435.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-217&quot; alt=&quot;Kayaking.. :)&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_0435.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Kayaking.. :)[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_218” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_0537.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-218&quot; alt=&quot;The natural jacuzzi bath&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_0537.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The natural jacuzzi bath[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;After Kayaking now it’s the turn to enjoy natural Jacuzzi bath. This one thing you should definitely not miss. The bath place is in the middle of the river where water gushes through certain rocky spaces where you can sit. The chilling water applies uniform pressure on your muscles which give u a sense of getting a good massage. It was a simply superb experience. I can still remember the noise made by the gushing water surrounding my body. Concentrating on that sound you will reach a peaceful state of mind forgetting all the tensions of daily life. But there is always an end to everything. We had to come out of natural Jacuzzi bath as the sun gradually set down saying “bye” to evening. With the immense satisfaction of a great experience, we headed back to our Pradhani village. On the way, we just stopped by the backwaters and Kali dam. The view was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_219” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_0553.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-219&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_0553&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_0553.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The gang[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;So after a fun-filled day we were back to jungle camp. Hmm so what next? Of course how can there not be a camp fire in such a place. After a quick refresh we all gathered around the camp fire. Guess what? we were not the only group of people in the jungle camp. So there is camp fire and bunch of friendly people.. that means &lt;em&gt;fun shuru ho jaye.&lt;/em&gt; Ahem.. Ahem.. For us the fun means dumb charades.. :P Dumb charades and Camp fire both ended at the same time. Now by this time we were really starving.. so it was time for hot food. The dinner was also good but this time we had both veg and non-veg options. The hunger for food was over but the hunger for fun was not even half complete. So we requested the manager to set a small campfire in front of our rooms. There were chit chats, dance and Mafia. Yes you read it right...Mafia.. Are baba.. it’s  a  game. Please google it out to know more about this game. More the number of people, more will be the fun in this game. It was almost 12:30 midnight when we all wished “ಶುಭರಾತ್ರಿ”(good night) to everyone and went to sleep. But before we went to bed, we all wished just for one thing...&quot;Let the Kali dam be open for tomo&quot;. Hmmm..why this specific wish?......... Because we were crazy about going rafting  :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;But as you people know God doesn’t grant all your wishes. We woke up at around 6:00 am to find out that we will not be able to raft... so you know what we did?... we went back to sleep… :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;Now, what can substitute the adventure and fun of rafting? Is it a trek to a waterfall in the middle of a forest? You bet.. Any trip with friends would be incomplete without a visit to waterfalls. So which one did we pick? Do you remember the absolutely splendid waterfalls shown in the recent Sharukh Khan movie “Chennai Express”? If you are a Kannada movie fan then you would have seen it in “Myna” movie too. If you have guessed it right... it’s none other than Dudhsagar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DudhSagar&lt;/strong&gt;
You can reach Dudhsagar either by road or by train but train route being the most popular. For people from Karnataka it is the Castle rock route. The distance from Dandeli to Castle Rock railway station is about 42.1 km. After reaching the Castle Rock railway station, you can either go by a train or hike on the railway track for about 14kms. Now comes the tricky part. There are no places to stay near Dudhsagar - obvious because it is in the middle of the forest. So you have to return back before the sun sets down unless you are crazy enough to roam like ghosts on a lonely railway track in a creepy jungle. Did I say lonely track? Yes because it is not a track where hundred’s of trains visit every day. According to the gyaan of the resort owner, there is just one train that stops at Castle Rock station. So you have to plan well in advance such that you don’t miss this train. The train leaves Castle Rock station by around 10:30 PM. Now once you board this train, make sure that you to go to unreserved compartments if you had bought a second class ticket otherwise you will end up in paying fine or bribe to the train TC as we did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;Enough of general information, now lets get back to our story. So we finished our breakfast the next day morning at Jungle camp and we are late. It’s almost 8:30 am and we have a train to catch that is 42kms away. The roads are very curvy and you can’t take the risk of riding fast unless you are a skillful driver. We were lucky because we had one. So after saying a sad good bye to Pradhani village and the jungle camp, we rushed towards the castle rock station. We worked on the game plan on the way as this train was our only chance to visit the spectacular Dudhsagar falls and we didn&#39;t want to screw it up at any cost. It was already 10.15 am. Pressure was building up. Whether we could catch the train or not. Everything was decided.. who has to get down first? Who has to get the tickets? Who has to get the food for afternoon meal? Who has to take care of luggage? Finally we reached the station. We saw the train standing in the station about to leave. One instruction in our minds - RUN! We ran as if we were chased by mad dogs. :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;Seriously, the 90 minutes train journey you must experience it once in your life. The lush greenery forest and in the middle, you and the train. You just can&#39;t sit back and enjoy. You have to stand near the door and feel it. And please don&#39;t forget to shout whenever the train enters the tunnel. The train reached Dudhsagar station and we were welcomed by a big yellow board and an old watch tower which had almost reached it&#39;s end of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_220” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_0595.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-220&quot; alt=&quot;Finally at Dudhsgar&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_0595.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Finally at Dudhsgar[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;You start walking in the direction of train for about 1 km and you can hear the noise of the mighty Dudhsagar. The railway track goes right in front of the waterfalls. When you go by the track you reach something like the middle of the falls. Either you can play there or you can decide to climb up or go down to the bottom of the waterfalls through a small path. But be careful as again there are chances of &quot;COMPLETE  ಹೊಗೆ&quot;. We decidde to go down after taking some pics near the falls as our souvenir. After we reached the bottom of the falls we couldn&#39;t just wait to swim. We wore our swim attire and literally just placed a foot into the water. For a moment it&#39;s like a thousand volts jhatka. The water was bone chillingly cold even with sun directly at the top in a warm afternoon. If you just walk a little bit doing circus on the slippery rocks you will reach a big pond at the bottom of the falls where you can swim(You are not allowed to go down during monsoons). Even if you are the best swimmer in the world you have to wear a  life jacket otherwise the life guards won&#39;t allow you to swim. So disappointed we walked back to the place where we changed our dress. The water from the falls flows further to this place where the force will be less and you can enjoy safely. Fun unlimited is guaranteed here. It can&#39;t be explained in words. You have to experience it yourselves. You can even watch the train going on the bridge from bottom of the falls. That is when you realize that there is a masterpiece of engineering in between the nature&#39;s beauty. Kudos to all the people who have built that bridge. So now the clock is ticking almost 4 PM in the evening and we had one thought in mind - &quot;Why the hell this time travels so fast? It used to be so much slow in our classrooms&quot;.. :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_215” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_0286.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-215&quot; alt=&quot;Dudhsagar falls and the train&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_0286.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Dudhsagar falls and the train[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;So me, Vijesh and Vivek were forced to stop playing by our friends. So we changed and started moving towards the Dudhsagar station. As you walk towards the station the mighty falls hides itself behind the tress and vanishes from your line of sight. When you reach the station you will  realize that how many people have come there like you. A huge crowd of more than 300 people at least were there. Now it is a challenge for you to board the train back to Castle Rock station which by the way stops only for 2 minutes at Dudhsagar. You have to personally experience that joy and huge cheer we witnessed by the crowd when the train arrived at 5:30 PM. We had to push in people to get inside the train. We were back to Castle Rock by 6:10 PM and we were all set to come back to Namma Bengaluru. So there it was; the end of a spectacular journey to Dandeli and Dudhsagar. We reached Bengaluru in the early morning and prepared ourselves (mentally) for a busy life with schedules, meetings, code reviews and commits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trip duration: &lt;/strong&gt;2 days, 1 night.
&lt;strong&gt;Travel distance:&lt;/strong&gt; 1000km (approx) for the complete journey
&lt;strong&gt;Approx cost: &lt;/strong&gt; ₹4500 (per head) [Travelling cost + stay and food at resort + Watersports + Dudhsagar]
&lt;strong&gt;Best time to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; June to December&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[googlemaps https://maps.google.co.in/maps?t=m&amp;amp;amp;sll=15.23137,74.2567214&amp;amp;amp;sspn=0.5089511,0.7034475&amp;amp;amp;geocode=Fbsj6AAd7J5xBCk_pKn7ReC-OzH4in1Dpm6GpA%3BFZMp5gAdACdxBCnn5GwiQua-OzH4c7d-8RI4DQ%3BFYPj6AAdDmNxBCkrO5_4PyC_OzEH8s36YXaKzQ%3BFUbx6gAdq09uBClRwD0zXQ-_OzGCyqF-NU24Kg%3BFSWu6QAdU_FtBCkhYDZcAAS_OzEXqx7Jy9iXow&amp;amp;amp;saddr=Pradhani,+Karnataka&amp;amp;amp;daddr=Syntheri+Rocks,+Gund,+Karnataka+581186+to:Bison+River+Resort,+Village+Ambeli+Post+Ganesh+Gudi,+State+Highway+34,+Badgund,+Karnataka+581186+to:Castlerock,+Karnataka+to:Dudhsagar+Falls&amp;amp;amp;dirflg=d&amp;amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;ll=15.231081,74.394406&amp;amp;amp;spn=0.416822,0.334959&amp;amp;amp;output=embed&amp;amp;w=425&amp;amp;h=350]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Venu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 10:19:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://sanchaara.in/adventure/castle%20rock/dandeli/dudhsagar/kayak/travel/western%20ghats/2014/03/16/dandeli-and-dudhsagar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sanchaara.in/adventure/castle%20rock/dandeli/dudhsagar/kayak/travel/western%20ghats/2014/03/16/dandeli-and-dudhsagar/</guid>
        
        
        <category>adventure</category>
        
        <category>castle rock</category>
        
        <category>dandeli</category>
        
        <category>dudhsagar</category>
        
        <category>kayak</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>western ghats</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 12:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://sanchaara.in/2014/03/14/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sanchaara.in/2014/03/14/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When life gives you coconuts, plan a trip to Kerala!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height:1.5em;&quot;&gt;One evening at home - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;Mom: I&#39;m bored.
Me: I&#39;m bored too. So yayy! lets go on a trip.
...and so it happened. Next was to decide upon a place. I wanted to go to Kerala for all the hype it had got. I was prepared for an argument with one strong point - my aunt stayed there. This made it easy to trick my parents into agreeing to my suggestion. &lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:cool:&quot; alt=&quot;:cool:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f192.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; Victory! Unanimous decision was to go to Kerala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;The complete trip was from 2nd Jan - 9th Jan. We boarded a train on 2nd Jan in Majestic to Thrisshur, Kerala. Reached Thrisshur the next morning. After endless chit chats over the dining table, it was time to hog.  After an authentic Kerala meal, we set out to explore the small city. Every street had a scenic touch to it. The small temples alongside the lakes were decorated with diyas that enhanced its beauty even more. Divine is the word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4th Jan, 2013.&lt;/strong&gt;
We rented a 4 seater car for the next 3 days of journey within Kerala. One of my cousin joined us. At around 8&#39;o clock we started from Thrisshur after having a sumptuous breakfast at my aunt&#39;s place. We stopped at Kalady, the place where Shankaracharya was born. A beautiful 8 storeyed temple that has Adi Shankara&#39;s story inscribed on the walls of the spiral interior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_181” align=”aligncenter” width=”225”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2398.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-181&quot; alt=&quot;Kalady&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2398.jpg?w=225&quot; width=&quot;225&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Kalady[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_178” align=”aligncenter” width=”200”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/imag0616.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-178 &quot; alt=&quot;IMAG0616&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/imag0616.jpg?w=200&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Shankaracharya’s idol at Kalady[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height:1.5em;&quot;&gt;Next stop was Munnar, one of the popular town situated on the Kannan Devan(sounds familiar?) hills in South India located in Idukki district of Kerala. It was 2 in the afternoon when we reached there. Our car broke down on a narrow road that led to Attukad waterfalls. The funny part was, the driver, a friend of my uncle who was the guide for the rest of our journey did not know Hindi and we did not know Malayalam. My dad tried to converse with him in Kannada with a Malayalam accent - I still dont know what exactly was my dad&#39;s strategy :P Thanks to my cousin who managed to make both the teams understand what was happening. At the end of the trip, she was all exhausted being a translator and chose to turn deaf ears to the rest of the conversation. Well, that&#39;s a completely different story. Anyway, why I brought this little problem of ours was to emphasize on how kind are Keralites. A gentleman led us to his cottage, beautifully placed amidst the hills, a faint music of the water flowing in the background - made me feel that life was perfect. His family offered us water and gave us tips on what to visit and what not to. Munnar in Malayalam means &quot;A land of 3 rivers&quot; - gyaan by locals at Munnar. While I, my cousin and my mom enjoyed the beauty of the place, my dad and driver fixed the car. We had lunch. I prefer not to add any superlative adjectives describing the quality of food. We stayed at a small hotel called Munnar gardens. After a moment of relaxation, we headed out to explore the place in the evening and what awaited us was this -&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2479.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-182 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;Munnar tea plantations&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2479.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_185” align=”aligncenter” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2552.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-185&quot; alt=&quot;Sometimes journey is more beautiful than the destination..&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2552.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Sometimes journey is more beautiful than the destination..[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2724.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-187&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_2724&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2724.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Echo point&lt;/strong&gt; surrounded by trees with a lake in between. It is said that a voice echoes for 7 times in this place. Crowded with tourists, this place has a lot of shops. Spicy peanuts, cotton candy, home made chocolates and soft toys are the majority commodities. (Sounds like a history lesson..eh? :P) You also get to do a horse ride for Rs.20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_192” align=”aligncenter” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2558.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-192&quot; alt=&quot;Echo point&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2558.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Echo point[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;Mattupetty dam. Whatte beauty! We were so busy in enjoying the view that we did not click any pictures here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;Rose park on the way back to hotel was another attraction. Fresh air, sunset, flowers and the people you love - a perfect evening. Mind you, this closes at 5.15pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5th Jan, 2013.&lt;/strong&gt;
What makes Munnar so scenic are its Tea plantations. There is a tea museum for the interested ones which explains the complete lifecycle of the tree leaves and its different types. There is also a video shown to the visitors that speaks about the history of Munnar and how the tea plantations came into existence there. At the exit, you get to sip free tea provided at the museum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2722.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-186 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_2722&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2722.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;Bidding a good bye to Munnar, we next headed towards Alleppy, mainly to experience the Kerala backwaters. If you ask me &quot;Does it look anything close to those pictures from Google?&quot; I say, &quot;Absolutely yes!&quot; Every bit of it is filled with so much beauty that it makes you feel that nature is a true artist to carefully place everything in right proportions. It was a boat ride of a lifetime that lasted for 2 full hours. It costed us Rs. 1000 plus a pic with white headed eagle *free free free* :D There are people who come here solely to stay over night in the House boat which costs around Rs. 10000 that lets a maximum of 10 people. Authentic Kerala fish food is served for meals. Best part is, the fishes are caught right there, out of the backwaters. Sleep peacefully while the river sings a lullaby to you :) After the boat ride, we rushed to the Alleppy beach to spend the rest of the evening there. Sunset was beautiful. The waves of the beach kissing your legs..there&#39;s nothing like it :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2923.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-193 aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_2923&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2923.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2954.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-188&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_2954&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2954.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_189” align=”alignnone” width=”750”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2962.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-189&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_2962.jpg?w=750&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;free free free&lt;/em&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a tiring day, we halted at one of the udupi hotels in Kochi. Decent room and a cat to keep us entertained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6th Jan, 2013.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Fort Kochi&lt;/strong&gt;, a cheerful region filled with tourists is bound by water. Fishing is a common sight here. &lt;strong&gt;St.Francis church&lt;/strong&gt; was all decorated with ribbons and balloons since it was just a week after Christmas. Vasco-da-gama&#39;s tomb is in this Church. &lt;strong&gt;Jewish synagogue&lt;/strong&gt; is another place. More than the place, the shops in the street leading to the synagogue catches your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_190” align=”aligncenter” width=”300”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_3117.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-190 &quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3117&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_3117.jpg?w=300&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; St. Francis church[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;A trip is not a trip unless you visit a waterfall. &lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:cool:&quot; alt=&quot;:cool:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f192.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; Attirapally waterfalls - yeah baby! :D
There&#39;s a lot to walk. So make sure you have had a good meal. You reach the head of the falls. Walk more to reach the foot of the falls. And there you are witnessing nature&#39;s beauty in its highest form. :) Watch out for the monkeys though :P I will let the picture do the talking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_191” align=”aligncenter” width=”592”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_3155.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-191 &quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3155&quot; src=&quot;http://sancharaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/03/img_3155.jpg?w=592&quot; width=&quot;592&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Atirapally waterfalls[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;Its for a reason they call it a God&#39;s own country and what&#39;s the reason - Well, can&#39;t help you here. You have to experience it yourself :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trip duration: &lt;/strong&gt;3 days, 2 night.
&lt;strong&gt;Travel distance:&lt;/strong&gt; 465km (approx) within Kerala.
&lt;strong&gt;Approx cost: &lt;/strong&gt; ₹4000 (per head)
&lt;strong&gt;Best time to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; October to January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[googlemaps https://maps.google.co.in/maps?f=d&amp;amp;amp;source=s_d&amp;amp;amp;saddr=Thrissur,+Kerala&amp;amp;amp;daddr=Kalady,+Kerala+to:Munnar,+Kerala+to:Alappuzha,+Kerala+to:Kochi,+Kerala+to:Athirapily+Water+falls,+Ayyampuzha,+Kerala+680724&amp;amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;amp;geocode=FZqjoAAdo_CKBCm70ULtFe6nOzHbp2wBqkUuCA%3BFfYjmwAdTGGOBCkTJpMnlQcIOzHGHzcBMoOzKw%3BFeXxmQAdxdWXBCltmglNeZkHOzEMfjxV5VAyBg%3BFdPtkAAdoNaMBClhaymq8YQIOzFa-EEsVWRHuA%3BFeGJlwAdKL-LBCm_xr5KUQ0IOzGSQYSlyoLVCw%3BFVDunAAdp1mQBCmFapg7IvkHOzELbDB3CggrcQ&amp;amp;amp;sll=10.013571,76.089653&amp;amp;amp;sspn=1.684982,2.526855&amp;amp;amp;mra=ls&amp;amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;ll=10.014834,76.088562&amp;amp;amp;spn=1.029951,0.852173&amp;amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;amp;output=embed&amp;amp;w=425&amp;amp;h=350]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Shruthi&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 21:18:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://sanchaara.in/family%20trips/2014/03/08/when-life-gives-you-coconuts-you-plan-a-trip-to-kerala/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sanchaara.in/family%20trips/2014/03/08/when-life-gives-you-coconuts-you-plan-a-trip-to-kerala/</guid>
        
        
        <category>family trips</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
